♪Minum ibun♪
♪미눔 이분♪
♪Your roots are holding tight♪
♪당신의 뿌리는 굳건히 자리잡고 있습니다♪
♪On this land♪
♪이 땅에서♪
♪Mengejar ombak♪
♪멘게자르 옴박♪
♪My leaves fly by♪
♪나의 나뭇잎이 날아간다♪
♪The border of thousands of stones♪
♪수천개의 돌의 경계♪
♪Looking at each other from afar♪
♪멀리서 서로를 바라보며♪
♪The edge of the cliff is♪
♪절벽의 끝은♪
♪Live together forever♪
♪영원히 함께 살아요♪
♪When we meet and part again♪
♪만나고 또 헤어지면♪
♪When we depend on each other and are far away♪
♪서로 의지 하고 멀리 떨어져 있을 때♪
♪I never forget♪
♪절대 잊지 않아요♪
♪The light reflected on the sword and knife♪
♪검과 칼에 반사되는 빛♪
♪Light up the dim sky♪
♪어두운 하늘을 밝혀주세요♪
♪Abandoned dreams♪
♪버려진 꿈♪
♪Shattered in the wind♪
♪바람에 부서지네♪
♪Against the direction of the wind and waves♪
♪바람과 파도의 반대방향♪
♪See thousands of ships crossing♪
♪수천 척의 배가 건너가는 모습을 보세요♪
♪This world changes♪
♪이 세상은 변한다♪
♪A suit of armor with make-up swinging in the wind♪
♪화장한 갑옷이 바람에 휘날리네요♪
♪Drinking ice, the blood is hard to be cold, dreaming of having fun in love♪
♪얼음을 마시고 피가 식지 않고 즐거운 사랑을 꿈꾸며♪
♪Just wish you were by my side♪
♪ 당신이 내 곁에 있었으면 좋겠어요 ♪
♪Don't waste spring time♪
♪봄날을 낭비하지 마세요♪
♪Trees reach the sky, roots connect, your friends uphold justice in the world♪
♪나무는 하늘에 닿고, 뿌리는 연결되고, 친구들은 세상의 정의를 수호합니다♪
♪Seeing the light flickering on the shoulder♪
♪어깨에 깜빡이는 빛을 보고♪
♪No regrets in this world♪
♪세상에 후회는 없어♪
=Wonderland of Love=
=사랑의 원더랜드=
=Episode 15=
=에피소드 15=
Leftenan He.
레프테난 그.
Is this all your plan?
이게 다 네 계획이야?
I said I don't know straight away.
나는 곧바로 모른다고 말했다.
You refuse to believe me?
당신은 내 말을 믿기를 거부합니까?
How can I trust you?
내가 너를 어떻게 믿어?
Stand there!
거기 서 있어!
(Which)
(어느)
Attack!
공격!
Don't fight anymore!
더 이상 싸우지 마세요!
Stop!
멈추다!
I know no matter what I say,
내가 무슨 말을 해도 알아요.
you won't believe it either.
당신도 그것을 믿지 않을 것입니다.
However, this time,
그러나 이번에는
I really don't know,
나는 정말로 모른다.
also never trapped you.
또한 결코 당신을 가두지 않았습니다.
Take the Cui Family Army away.
Cui Family 군대를 제거하십시오.
If you dare appear in front of me again,
감히 다시 내 앞에 나타난 다면
I will kill anyone
난 누구든지 죽일 거야
that i see
내가 보는 것
Release them!
그들을 풀어주세요!
Since leaving the Laolan Border,
라오란 국경을 떠난 이후,
I didn't think so
나는 그렇게 생각하지 않았다
our great failure
우리의 큰 실패
due to defection
탈북으로 인해
That vile Cui.
그 사악한 Cui.
Gather our men and horses
우리의 병력과 말을 모아라
and retreated to Luoyang slowly.
천천히 낙양으로 후퇴했습니다 .
Of.
의.
Lieutenant He, let's eat.
중위님, 식사하세요.
The incident at the Tong border
통 국경에서의 사건
definitely Young Master Cui's plan.
확실히 최영사님의 계획이군요.
I'm satisfied I asked earlier,
아까 물어봤는데 만족해요
the team leader refused to say anything.
팀 리더는 아무 말도 거부했습니다.
He just said,
그는 방금 이렇게 말했습니다.
Young Master Cui directed them there.
최 젊은 스승은 그들을 그곳으로 인도했습니다.
In fact, they are directed
실제로 그들은 지시를 받습니다.
go away
저리 가요
to lure us to a distant place.
우리를 먼 곳으로 유인하기 위해.
Others,
기타,
he refused to speak again.
그는 다시 말하기를 거부했습니다.
He said himself
그 자신이 말했다
don't know anything
아무것도 몰라
Leftenan He,
레프테난 그,
eat a little
조금 먹어
After a meal,
식사 후,
we just plan again.
우리는 다시 계획을 세웁니다.
Li Ni is bad.
리니가 나빠요.
Without investigating this,
이를 조사하지 않고,
he continues to slander you.
그는 계속해서 당신을 비방하고 있습니다.
You don't know anything,
당신은 아무것도 모르고,
He also wants to say that you conspired with Young Master Cui.
그는 또한 당신이 최영선생과 공모했다고 말하고 싶어합니다 .
Furious!
맹렬한!
Our Cui Family army caused
우리 추이 가문 군대가 일으킨
The Zhenxi Army lost the Tong Border
Zhenxi 군대는 Tong 국경을 잃었습니다.
and many soldiers were injured.
그리고 많은 군인들이 부상을 입었습니다.
That is the truth.
그것은 진실입니다.
If I were in his situation,
내가 그 사람의 상황이었다면,
I can't be calm either .
나도 안심할 수가 없어.
However, I remember
그러나 나는 기억한다
he will trust me.
그는 나를 믿을 것이다.
Enough already,
이미 충분히,
don't think much more.
더 이상 생각하지 마십시오.
However,
하지만,
he is a wise man.
그는 현명한 사람입니다.
He will surely understand later.
그 사람은 나중에 분명히 이해하게 될 거예요.
Look at you.
당신을 보면.
Tuan Shiqi,
투안 시치,
why didn't you wake me up?
왜 나를 깨우지 않았어?
You stayed up all night.
당신은 밤새도록 깨어 있었어요.
I'm not sleepy.
나는 안 졸려.
This is nothing.
이것은 아무것도 아니다.
You know
알잖아
even though Lieutenant He has many tricks,
중위님은 많은 트릭을 갖고 계시지만,
but he
그러나 그는
be frank.
솔직해지세요.
Even if he deceives us,
그 사람이 우리를 속여도
won't he dare admit it.
그는 감히 그것을 인정하지 않을 것입니다.
Ying,
잉,
finally able to welcome you.
드디어 여러분을 맞이할 수 있게 되었습니다.
You defected at the Tong Border?
통국경에서 탈북했다고요 ?
Ying,
잉,
Sun Jing has agreed.
Sun Jing이 동의했습니다.
As long as we cooperate with him to conquer the Tong Border
우리가 그와 협력하여 통 국경을 정복하는 한
dan menghalau Tentera Zhenxi,
단 멘갈라우 텐테라 젠시,
he will withdraw the troops sent to Yingzhou.
그는 영주로 파견된 군대를 철수할 것이다 .
Therefore,
그러므로,
solve the problem on the father's side.
아버지 쪽에서 문제를 해결하세요.
How can you do that?
어떻게 했니?
Why can't I do that?
나는 왜 그렇게 할 수 없습니까?
I won't
나는하지 않을 것이다
let dad
아빠를 보자
besieged by Sun Jing's army?
Sun Jing의 군대에 의해 포위되었습니까?
did you know,
알고 계셨나요?
we are allied with the Zhenxi Army?
우리는 Zhenxi 군대와 동맹을 맺고 있습니까?
That's a desperate deal .
정말 절망적인 거래네요.
It's not like you don't know Li Ni's nature.
리니의 성격을 모르는 것은 아닙니다.
He is always changeable.
그는 항상 변할 수 있습니다.
Who knows after he conquers
정복한 뒤에는 누가 알겠어요?
The capital city of Xichang later,
나중에 수도인 시창(Xichang)에
will he send troops to Yingzhou immediately
그는 즉시 잉저우에 군대를 보낼 것인가?
to urge the Cui Family Army and my father?
Cui 가족 군대 와 아버지를 촉구하기 위해?
why you
왜 네가
didn't talk to me before doing that?
그 전에는 나한테 얘기 안 했어?
All my actions are for the good of the Cui Family Army.
나의 모든 행동은 추이 가문 군대 의 이익을 위한 것입니다 .
Tentera Zhenxi
텐테라 젠시
lost some soldiers and horses
군인과 말 몇 명을 잃었습니다
as well as Borders of Tongs only.
집게의 테두리만 가능합니다.
Since Li Ni is so great,
리니가 너무 대단해서,
he can
그는 할 수있다
fight back later.
나중에 반격하세요.
The situation in Yingzhou is very critical,
잉저우의 상황은 매우 심각합니다.
won't I not have to save my father?
내가 아버지를 구하지 않아도 되는 거 아냐 ?
Of course we must save him,
물론 우리는 그를 구해야 합니다.
tapi Tentera Zhenxi
타피 텐테라 젠시
received the Cui Family Army with good will.
선의로 추이 가문 군대를 받았습니다 .
You shouldn't have defected at the Tong Border.
통국경에서 탈북하지 말았 어야 했습니다 .
I just want to
나는 그저 원할 뿐이야
solve the problem in Yingzhou.
Yingzhou의 문제를 해결하십시오.
Ying,
잉,
if you
만약 너라면
likes Li Ni and doesn't know the difference between official things and personal things,
리니를 좋아하고 공적인 일과 사적인 일을 구분하지 못하고 ,
so you asked me,
그래서 나한테 물었잖아.
do you think this is fair?
이게 공평하다고 생각하세요?
young sir,
젊은 선생님,
should i chase him?
내가 그 사람을 쫓아야 하나?
Taozi was by his side,
도자가 그의 곁에 있었고,
he won't go far.
그는 멀리 가지 않을 것이다.
When he is open-minded later,
나중에 마음이 열리면,
surely he will come back.
반드시 그는 돌아올 것이다.
Leftenan He,
레프테난 그,
what do you say we'll go back first?
우리 먼저 돌아가자고 뭐라고 했어?
Actually,
실제로,
Young Master Cui did it for Yingzhou's sake.
최 젊은 스승은 잉저우를 위해 그렇게 했습니다.
I know.
알아요.
However, the way he works
그러나 그가 일하는 방식은
incorrect.
잘못된.
Don't be sad anymore.
더 이상 슬퍼하지 마세요.
I'm not sad.
나 슬프지 않아.
Just me...
나만...
You are worried
당신은 걱정하고 있습니다
Li Ni doesn't understand and
Li Ni는 이해하지 못하고
keep misunderstanding you?
계속 오해하고 있어?
Enough already.
이미 충분합니다.
Later, don't bring that person up again.
나중에 그 사람 다시는 꺼내지 마세요.
Since he doesn't trust me,
그 사람이 나를 믿지 않으니까,
when we meet again,
우리가 다시 만날때,
we are just strangers.
우리는 단지 낯선 사람입니다.
afraid we will only meet in war later.
나중에 전쟁에서 만날까 두렵습니다 .
Even so, we don't need to be afraid either.
그렇다고 우리도 두려워할 필요는 없습니다.
Despite how great Li Ni is,
리니가 아무리 대단해도
surely he can't be defeated
확실히 그 사람은 패배할 수 없어
our commander in chief.
우리 총사령관.
Honestly,
솔직히,
as we leave Yingzhou,
잉저우를 떠나면서
I am thinking,
내가 생각하고,
the common people are indeed innocent.
일반 사람들은 참으로 결백합니다.
Sun Jing
순징
rampant and yearning for great success.
만연하고 큰 성공을 갈망합니다.
He fought desperately
그는 필사적으로 싸웠다
to conquer Baiyue.
바이웨를 정복하기 위해.
Only by fighting Sun Jing
쑨징과 싸워야만
so that the country is peaceful,
나라가 평화로워지도록
then the common people can live well.
그러면 서민들이 잘 살 수 있다.
However, I didn't think so
하지만, 나는 그렇게 생각하지 않았다
the existence of talent like Li Ni in the Li Family.
Li Family에 Li Ni와 같은 인재가 존재합니다 .
Actually,
실제로,
based on good name,
좋은 이름을 바탕으로,
morals and abilities,
도덕성과 능력,
he is also the person who can reconcile the world
세상을 화해시킬 수 있는 사람 이기도 하다
so that the common people can live well.
서민들이 잘 살 수 있도록.
Leftenan He,
레프테난 그,
in the past, you think
과거에 당신은 생각
only you
오직 너
and the Cui Family Army
그리고 추이 가문 군대
that can reconcile the world.
세상을 화해시킬 수 있는 것입니다.
Of.
의.
I did not expect
나는 기대하지 않았다
going to meet this person.
이 사람을 만나러 갑니다.
However,
하지만,
maybe we will become enemies later.
어쩌면 우리는 나중에 적이 될 수도 있습니다.
What say we go back first?
우리 먼저 돌아가는 게 어때요?
Young Master Cui must be very worried about you.
최영스승님이 당신을 많이 걱정하셨나 봐요.
Now
지금
can only rush to Yingzhou first.
먼저 Yingzhou로 달려갈 수 있습니다.
Return early to meet the commander-in-chief,
일찍 돌아와서 총사령관을 만나고,
He must be very loving.
그는 매우 사랑이 많음에 틀림없습니다.
Good.
좋은.
Wait a minute, I'll bring you food.
잠깐만요, 음식 가져올게요.
In these few days,
요 며칠 동안,
Tentera Zhenxi yang diambil dan
텐테라 젠시 양 디암빌 단
those who retreated from the Tong Border,
통 국경에서 후퇴한 사람들,
everything is here.
모든 것이 여기에 있습니다.
However, if we go to Luoyang with this condition,
그러나 이 조건으로 낙양에 가면
King Linzi was afraid of suspicion.
Linzi 왕은 의심을 두려워했습니다.
My eldest brother
나의 큰 형
ambitious, but not highly capable.
야망은 있지만 능력이 뛰어나지는 않습니다.
In fact, he was discouraged.
사실 그는 낙담했습니다.
I'm your brother too
나도 네 동생이야
most cunning.
가장 교활하다.
He was by my eldest brother's side,
그 사람은 내 큰 형 옆에 있었는데,
I don't know what trick he will come up with.
그 사람이 무슨 계략을 펼칠지 모르겠네요 .
Then why did we retreat to Luoyang?
그렇다면 우리는 왜 낙양으로 후퇴했는가?
We lost the Barrel Border
우리는 배럴 국경을 잃었습니다
and could only take these armies,
이 군대 만 점령할 수 있었고 ,
King Linzi will indeed
린자왕은 과연 그럴 것이다.
look down on us.
우리를 내려다보세요.
However, as long as your father
하지만, 네 아버지가 있는 한
still leading the Zhenxi Army,
여전히 진시군을 이끌고 있으며,
he didn't even dare to treat us badly.
그는 감히 우리를 나쁘게 대하지 도 않았습니다 .
We'll see,
우리는 보자
most likely he will send someone to come
아마 그 사람이 누군가를 보내서 올 거야
and pretended to say hello.
그리고 인사하는 척 했어요.
Tuan Shiqi.
투안시치.
Talk.
말하다.
King Linzi heard that we retreated from the Tong Border,
임자왕은 우리가 동국에서 퇴각했다는 소식을 듣고
so he recruited people from Luoyang
그래서 그는 낙양에서 사람들을 모집했습니다.
send food to come
음식을 보내다 오다
to make a donation.
기부를 하려고.
Tuan Shiqi,
투안 시치,
Your guess is correct.
당신의 추측이 정확합니다.
In that case,
그 경우,
we just accept it.
우리는 그것을 받아들입니다.
Deliver my instructions,
내 지시를 전달하고,
set up a tent here and make arrangements for a few days,
여기에 텐트를 치고 며칠간 준비를 하고,
then left for Luoyang.
그런 다음 낙양으로 떠났습니다.
Of.
의.
Sister.
자매.
Sister said Li Ni had a failure,
언니는 Li Ni가 실패했다고 했어요.
so you tell your brother to send food and donations
그래서 형한테 음식이랑 기부금 보내라고 했어
to them.
그들에게.
Your brother sent it,
형이 보냈어.
but I didn't think so
하지만 난 그렇게 생각하지 않았어
he accepted it all.
그는 그것을 모두 받아들였습니다.
Sister,
자매,
this is cunning
이건 교활하다
Li Ni.
리니.
He knew he had failed big,
그는 자신이 큰 실패를 했다는 것을 알았습니다.
of course your brother accepted him and his army,
물론 네 형은 그와 그의 군대를 받아들였지.
but, don't be embarrassed
하지만, 당황하지 마세요
he received your brother's contribution as well.
그 사람도 당신 동생의 공헌을 받았어요.
Obviously he plans to
분명히 그 사람은 그럴 계획이야
depends on your brother.
형에 따라 다릅니다.
Brother must
형제는 해야 한다
appreciate this opportunity.
이 기회에 감사드립니다.
However, there were still tens of thousands of Zhenxi soldiers and horses
그러나 아직 진희의 병사와 말이 수만 명에 달했다.
yang dipimpin Pei Xian.
양 디핀핀 페이 시안.
Everything is ready in the back.
뒤쪽에는 모든 것이 준비되어 있습니다.
Is your brother afraid?
형이 무서워?
As long as Li Ni entered Luoyang,
Li Ni가 Luoyang에 들어가는 한,
Your brother can conspire with the officers
네 형 이 장교들과 공모 할 수도 있어
to question him about the failure at the Tong Border.
통 국경에서의 실패에 대해 그에게 질문합니다 .
Therefore,
그러므로,
it's easy for your brother to deprive him of his military power.
당신의 형이 그의 군사력을 빼앗기는 것은 쉽습니다 .
What if Pei Xian feels offended?
Pei Xian이 기분이 상했다면 어떻게 하나요 ?
Your father has ascended the throne,
네 아버지가 왕위에 오르셨느니라.
his majesty
폐하
If he's not satisfied,
그 사람이 만족하지 못한다면,
it means he does not respect the emperor.
이는 그가 황제를 존경하지 않는다는 뜻이다.
People who do not respect the emperor
황제를 존경하지 않는 사람들
can be killed by anyone.
누구든지 죽일 수 있습니다.
Your words make sense.
당신의 말은 의미가 있습니다.
Your brother has someone write a letter to Li Ni immediately.
당신의 형은 즉시 Li Ni에게 편지를 쓰도록 누군가에게 요청했습니다 .
Since he had failed,
그가 실패했기 때문에,
then he needs to bring his army
그럼 그 사람은 군대를 데려와야 해
return to the palace immediately
즉시 궁으로 돌아가라
and follow instructions.
그리고 지시를 따르세요.
Why didn't your brother take this opportunity?
네 형은 왜 이 기회를 잡지 않았니?
to eliminate the enemy once and for all?
적을 완전히 제거하려면?
You mean
네 말 뜻은
The Cui Family Army?
추이 가문 군대?
Of.
의.
Didn't your brother lend it?
형이 빌려주지 않았어?
a troop of light cavalry carrying crossbows
석궁 을 들고 있는 경기병 부대
to Cui Li before?
예전에 Cui Li에게?
Unfortunately Cui Li acted rashly
불행히도 Cui Li는 성급하게 행동했습니다.
and let Cui Lin escape.
그리고 추이린을 탈출시키세요.
As a result, he was saved by Li Ni.
그 결과 그는 Li Ni에 의해 구해졌습니다.
Your brother is also worried that Cui Li is not mature
네 형도 최리가 성숙하지 못한 걸 걱정하고 있어
and reveal this,
이걸 공개하고,
that's hard.
그건 어렵다.
Sister,
자매,
this is a good time to
지금이 좋은 시간이야
Cui Li killed Cui Lin.
Cui Li는 Cui Lin을 죽였습니다.
Try to think, Cui Lin just defected at the Tong Border,
생각해 보세요, Cui Lin은 방금 Tong Border에서 탈북했습니다.
Li Ni hates him very much.
Li Ni는 그를 매우 싫어합니다.
After all,
결국,
if Cui Lin dies at this time,
이때 추이린이 죽으면
Even Cui Yi would not be suspicious.
Cui Yi조차도 의심하지 않을 것입니다.
He must have remembered it was Li Ni's crime.
그는 그것이 Li Ni의 범죄라는 것을 기억했을 것입니다.
Cui Yi only had one son.
최이에게는 아들이 하나뿐이었습니다.
If he loses a son in old age now,
지금 노년에 아들을 잃으면
surely he will fight to the death with Li Ni.
분명히 그는 Li Ni와 함께 죽을 때까지 싸울 것입니다 .
Good!
좋은!
(Sister Ni, since your brother knew you had a failure at the Tong Border,)
(니자매님, 통보더에서 실패했다는 것을 형님이 아셨기 때문에 )
(your brother feels heartbroken)
(동생이 마음이 아팠어요)
(and worry.)
(그리고 걱정합니다.)
(Previous contribution)
(이전 기여)
(may not be enough,)
(충분하지 않을 수도 있습니다.)
(quickly bring your brother's army back to rest.)
(빨리 형의 군대를 다시 쉬게 하라.)
(From your brother)
(형님한테서)
King Linzi told us to return to Luoyang immediately?
임자왕이 우리에게 즉시 낙양으로 돌아가라고 하였습니까?
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
I guess he felt it
그 사람도 느꼈을 것 같은데
failure at the Tong border
통 국경에서의 실패
can strip
벗길 수 있다
my military power.
나의 군사력.
He is not good at fighting,
그 사람은 싸움을 잘 못하는데,
but good at playing dirty tricks.
하지만 더러운 장난을 잘 치는군요.
The army that my father sent
아버지가 보낸 군대
will arrive in a few days.
며칠 안에 도착할 거예요.
Before the army leaves, we need to prepare food first.
군대가기 전에 먼저 음식을 준비해야 해요.
We have to plan
우리는 계획을 세워야 해
food first.
음식 먼저.
Li Ni has delivered the news.
리니가 소식을 전했습니다.
You sent someone to answer Li Ni.
Li Ni에게 대답하기 위해 누군가를 보냈습니다.
If he can keep his promise,
그 사람이 약속을 지킬 수 있다면,
welcoming the return of the emperor's great-grandson and guaranteeing the emperor's great-grandson
황제의 증손자의 귀환을 환영하고 황제의 증손자를 보장함
can grow up to be an adult,
어른으로 성장할 수 있고,
ascend the throne,
왕좌에 오르다,
his position restored as crown prince,
왕세자로서의 지위를 회복하고 ,
I would agree.
동의합니다.
Of.
의.
(Gu's residence)
(구 거주지)
Father told me to come suddenly,
아버지가 갑자기 오라고 하셔서
is there anything important?
중요한 게 있어?
Dad just received the news,
아빠가 방금 소식을 들었어.
The army that attacked Baiyue has been defeated.
백월을 공격한 군대는 패배했다.
Reportedly, the governor was furious
주지사는 분노했다고 한다
and give instructions to block this news.
그리고 이 뉴스를 차단하라는 지시를 내립니다.
However, the news is blocked
그런데 뉴스가 차단됐네요
often
자주
spread quickly.
빠르게 퍼졌습니다.
What is your father's opinion?
아버지의 의견은 어떻습니까?
In my father's view,
아버지의 입장에서는,
if they really lose,
만약 그들이 정말로 졌다면,
the news is impossible
그 소식은 불가능하다
spread so quickly.
너무 빨리 퍼졌습니다.
I think so
그렇게 생각해요
is that Sun Jing's plan?
그게 Sun Jing의 계획인가요?
Of.
의.
That was Sun Jing's tactic
그게 쑨징의 전술이었어
to lure the snake out of the hole.
뱀을 구멍 밖으로 유인하기 위해.
Anyone who dares
감히 누구든지
acting recklessly at the moment,
지금은 무모하게 행동하고,
then that person will be caught in his trap.
그러면 그 사람은 함정에 빠지게 될 것이다.
Ying.
잉.
Young master.
젊은 주인님.
Taozi,
타오지,
I have something to talk to Ying.
잉이랑 할 얘기가 있어요.
Of.
의.
Ying,
잉,
spies deliver the news
스파이가 소식을 전하다
Sun Jing failed to conquer Baiyue.
Sun Jing은 Baiyue를 정복하지 못했습니다.
Ying,
잉,
are you
당신은
still mad at me?
아직도 나한테 화났어?
This time,
이 시간,
young master cheated me too.
젊은 주인님도 나를 속였습니다.
I just feel sad.
그냥 슬프다.
Because, Sun Jing promised to
왜냐하면 Sun Jing은 다음과 같이 약속했기 때문입니다.
withdrew troops from Yingzhou,
영주에서 군대를 철수했다.
I just made the Barrel Boundary as a condition of exchange.
그냥 교환조건으로 Barrel Boundary를 만들어 봤습니다 .
Why are you hiding this from me?
왜 나 한테 이걸 숨기는 거야?
Why did you cheat on me?
왜 나를 속였나요?
Ying,
잉,
we both
우리 모두
grew up together since childhood.
어린 시절부터 함께 자랐습니다.
No matter what you think,
당신이 어떻게 생각하든,
I have considered you as my closest person.
나는 당신을 가장 가까운 사람으로 여겼습니다 .
I...
나...
I never thought of hiding this from you or deceiving you.
나는 이 사실을 당신에게 숨기거나 속일 생각은 한 번도 해본 적이 없습니다.
Just you
너 뿐이야
out with Li Ni,
Li Ni와 함께,
I don't want him to know.
나는 그 사람이 알기를 원하지 않습니다.
Good plan young master this time.
이번에는 좋은 계획 젊은 스승님.
You know as long as I gather with the Cui Family Army,
내가 최씨족 군대와 함께 모이기만 하면 ,
Li Ni will definitely come along,
리니가 꼭 따라올 거야
you can act too.
당신도 행동할 수 있다.
I do think for the good of the Cui Family Army.
나는 Cui Family Army의 이익을 위해 생각합니다 .
Now I'm really curious too
이제 나도 정말 궁금하다
you think
당신 생각에는
for whose sake?
누구를 위해서?
What makes you angry and upset?
무엇이 당신을 화나게 하고 속상하게 만드나요?
Is it because of Li Ni,
리니 때문인가,
you even forget the origin
원산지조차 잊어버리셨군요
and the reason we left Yingzhou?
그리고 우리가 Yingzhou를 떠난 이유는 무엇입니까?
Ying.
잉.
The young master just went back to rest.
젊은 주인은 방금 휴식을 취하기 위해 돌아갔습니다.
It's a waste
낭비야
young master talks a lot.
젊은 스승님이 말을 많이 하십니다.
With a good count,
좋은 카운트와 함께,
we can use 10 thousand soldiers in hand
병력 1만명을 손에 넣을 수 있다
to attack the Capital City of Xichang.
수도인 시창(Xichang)을 공격합니다.
You want to attack 100 thousand soldiers with 10 thousand soldiers?
1만명의 병사로 10만명의 병사를 공격하시겠습니까 ?
Didn't Sun Jing want to bait the snake out of the hole?
Sun Jing은 뱀을 구멍 밖으로 끌어내고 싶지 않았나요 ?
We act according to his plan.
우리는 그의 계획에 따라 행동합니다.
He pretended to lose,
그는 지는 척을 했고,
I will let him really lose.
나는 그가 정말로 지게 놔둘 것이다.
Tuan Shiqi,
투안 시치,
I have something important to talk to you about.
당신에게 중요한 이야기가 있습니다 .
What thing?
무슨 일이?
Come here.
이리 오세요.
Can't you talk in front of me?
내 앞에서 얘기하면 안 돼요?
Are you arguing with Young Master Cui?
최영선생과 논쟁 중이신가요?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
Oh yes,
바로 이거 야,
there's news from the capital
수도에서 소식이 있어
the army that attacked Baiyue had lost.
백월을 공격한 군대는 패했다.
Sun Jing blocked this news now.
Sun Jing은 지금 이 뉴스를 차단했습니다.
In that case,
그 경우,
meaning there are not many soldiers
군인이 많지 않다는 뜻이다.
by Sun Jing's side now?
지금은 Sun Jing 옆에 있나요?
Leftenan He,
레프테난 그,
should we
우리는
inform the commander-in-chief immediately
즉시 총사령관에게 알린다.
to go besiege Sun Jing?
Sun Jing을 포위하러 갈까요?
It's not bad yet.
아직 나쁘지 않습니다.
I think this is a bit strange.
제 생각에는 이것이 좀 이상한 것 같아요.
Maybe this was Sun Jing's tactic.
아마도 이것이 Sun Jing의 전술이었을 것입니다.
Li Ni...
리니...
That person...
저 사람...
The person you won't let me mention,
언급하지 말라고 한 사람 ,
will he be trapped?
그 사람 갇힐까?
So.
그래서.
He is brave and conscientious.
그는 용감하고 성실합니다.
Rarely is he baited with goodness.
그가 선함으로 미끼를 받는 경우는 거의 없습니다.
Sun Jing pretended to lose,
Sun Jing은 지는 척했고,
surely he knows about it.
확실히 그는 그것에 대해 알고 있습니다.
After all, this
결국, 이것은
is an opportunity for him.
그에게는 기회다.
He will not miss this opportunity.
그는 이 기회를 놓치지 않을 것이다.
Yes?
예?
What will he do?
그는 무엇을 할 것인가?
He will
그는 할 것이다
act according to Sun Jing's tactics.
Sun Jing의 전술에 따라 행동하십시오.
You mean,
네 말 뜻은,
Cui Li is still patrolling and ambushing by the river?
Cui Li가 아직도 강을 순찰하고 매복하고 있다고요?
Of.
의.
We need to gather with
우리는 함께 모여야 한다
the army sent by Commander-in-Chief Pei
페이 총사령관이 파견한 군대
and set up a military camp.
그리고 군사 캠프를 설치합니다.
Mind you,
명심하세요.
menurut amalan Tentera Zhenxi,
메뉴루트 아말란 텐테라 젠시(Tentera Zhenxi),
we will send some small forces
우리는 작은 병력을 보낼 것입니다
to patrol to dozens of miles
수십 마일을 순찰하다
before choosing a military camp area.
군사 캠프 지역을 선택하기 전에 .
My little team goes further,
나의 작은 팀은 더 나아가,
by chance we bumped into
우연히 우리가 마주쳤어
Cui Li who led the army.
군대를 이끌었던 최리.
Apparently, he was ready for an ambush at night.
분명히 그는 밤에 매복할 준비가 되어 있었습니다.
Cui Li ready to ambush?
추이 리(Cui Li)가 매복할 준비가 되었나요?
Of course he wants to
물론 그는 원한다
attacked Young Master Cui.
최영스승을 공격했다.
However,
하지만,
Leftenan He
레프테난 그
with Young Master Cui now.
지금 최영스승과 함께.
Do we want to save it?
저장하시겠습니까?
So.
그래서.
Very?
매우?
Of.
의.
young sir,
젊은 선생님,
Cui Lin and others
추이린 외
will arrive in half an hour.
30분 후에 도착할 거예요.
Deliver my instructions,
내 지시를 전달하고,
everyone get ready
다들 준비하세요
and cheer up.
그리고 힘내세요.
After Cui Lin was killed,
추이린이 살해된 후,
everyone will be rewarded.
모두가 보상을 받을 것입니다.
Of.
의.
Leftenan He!
좌파 그!
Sir,
선생님,
we didn't succeed before.
우리는 전에 성공하지 못했습니다.
We must succeed
우리는 성공해야 한다
in action this time.
이번에는 활동 중입니다.
If we can't kill Cui Lin this time,
이번에 추이린을 죽이지 못한다면
we will lose a big support
우리는 큰 지지를 잃게 될 것이다
from the King of Linzi, Li Jun.
임자왕 이준에게서.
After Cui Lin returns later,
나중에 추이린이 돌아온 후,
he and uncle will not let me go.
그와 삼촌은 나를 놓아주지 않을 것입니다.
However,
하지만,
Cui Lin must die.
추이린은 죽어야 한다.
I remember
기억해
you want to shoot Lieutenant He.
당신은 He 중위를 쏘고 싶어합니다.
You have a tough mouth, but a soft heart.
입은 거칠지만 마음은 여린 당신.
Young master!
젊은 주인님!
Ying.
잉.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Why didn't you show up after I was killed later?
나중에 내가 죽은 뒤에 왜 나타나지 않았나요 ?
You have arrived at the very beginning,
당신은 맨 처음에 도착했습니다.
but, until now you are down.
하지만 지금까지 당신은 다운되었습니다.
You did it on purpose.
일부러 그러셨군요.
Of,
의,
I did it on purpose.
일부러 그랬어요.
Didn't think so
그렇게 생각하지 않았어
you have succeeded
당신은 성공했습니다
prince,
왕자,
we are indeed putting ourselves at risk
우리는 실제로 우리 자신을 위험에 빠뜨리고 있습니다
to kill Cui Lin this time.
이번에는 추이린을 죽이려고 합니다.
However,
하지만,
for the success of the prince,
왕자님의 성공을 위해
it's worth it.
그것은 가치.
You have worked hard.
당신은 열심히 일했습니다.
I will remember your service.
나는 당신의 봉사를 기억할 것입니다.
You will earn
당신은 적립됩니다
what you deserve
당신은 무엇을받을 자격이
I reminisce
나는 회상한다
good lord prince
맙소사 왕자님
Later, I will definitely serve the prince faithfully.
나중에는 반드시 왕자님을 충실히 섬길 것입니다.
(Which)
(어느)
(Paglima Besar Pingliang, Cui Yi)
(Paglima Besar Pingliang, Cui Yi)
I am the commander in chief of the Cui Family Army,
나는 최씨군 총사령관이다 .
Panglima Besar Pingliang, Cui Yi.
Panglima Besar Pingliang, Cui Yi.
You go up.
올라가세요.
If you admit defeat, you will not be killed.
패배를 인정하면 죽지 않습니다.
The governor ordered us to attack Yingzhou,
주지사는 우리에게 영주를 ​​공격하라고 명령했습니다.
anyone who escapes will be killed,
도망치는 사람은 모두 죽임을 당할 것이다.
anyone who admits defeat will be killed.
패배를 인정하는 사람은 누구나 죽임을 당할 것이다.
My whole family
나의 가족 전부
supervised by the village head.
마을 이장이 감독한다.
If I admit defeat,
패배를 인정한다면,
my whole family will be killed.
우리 가족 모두가 죽임을 당할 것입니다.
Tuan,
투안,
Sun Jing's army has been half wiped out.
Sun Jing의 군대는 절반이 전멸되었습니다.
The other half ran away.
나머지 절반은 도망갔습니다.
What do we say?
우리는 무엇을 말합니까?
follow them
그들을 따라가
to the capital city of Xichang?
수도인 시창으로 가나요?
Grand Commander Cui!
추이 대사령관!
Grand Commander Cui.
추이 대사령관.
On the way Young Master Cui
가는 길에 최영선생
lead the army back to the army camp,
군대를 다시 군대 캠프로 이끌어라.
he was ambushed
그는 매복을 당했다
and fell into the water with serious injuries.
그리고 물에 빠져 심각한 부상을 입었습니다.
Now his position is unknown.
이제 그의 위치는 알려지지 않았습니다.
Where is the person by his side?
옆에 있는 사람은 어디에 있나요?
Where is Lieutenant He?
그 중위는 어디에 있습니까?
When Young Master Cui was ambushed,
최영대사가 매복 공격을 받았을 때,
it just so happened that the Zhenxi Army was nearby
우연히 진시군이 근처에 있었던 거야
and save some people.
그리고 몇 사람을 구해 보세요.
Ketua panglima Tentera Zhenxi, Li Ni
Ketua panglima Tentera Zhenxi, Li Ni
write a letter
편지 쓰기
and deploy people to send to you.
그리고 당신에게 보낼 사람들을 배치하세요.
(Grand Commander Cui,)
(최대사령관)
(when the Cui Family Army was ambushed,)
(최씨군이 매복 공격을 받았을 때)
(we happen to be nearby,)
(우린 근처에 있었어,)
(but, unfortunately we are late)
(하지만 아쉽게도 우리는 늦었다)
(and Young Master Cui has fallen into the river.)
(그리고 최선생은 강에 빠졌습니다.)
(Luckily we were able to save Ying)
(다행히 잉을 구출할 수 있었습니다)
(to calm your heart.)
(마음을 안정시키기 위해)
(Ying is fine and resting at the Zhenxi Army camp.)
(잉은 건강하고 진시군 캠프에서 쉬고 있다.)
(I hope you can lead the armed forces)
(당신 이 군대를 이끌 수 있기를 바랍니다 )
(and conquered Xichang Capital with the Zhenxi Army.)
( 진서군으로 서 창성을 함락시켰다 .)
Disgusting Li Ni
역겨운 리니
and really arrogant.
그리고 정말 거만해요.
Dare he...
감히 그 사람이...
How dare he threaten me!
그가 감히 나를 위협하다니!
Ying.
잉.
Lieutenant He, take medicine.
그 중위님, 약 드세요.
It's too hot, I'll drink later.
너무 더워서 나중에 마실게요.
Don't be too sad.
너무 슬퍼하지 마세요.
Young Master Cui...
영 마스터 쿠이...
Maybe Tuan Muda Cui has been saved by someone.
어쩌면 Tuan Muda Cui가 누군가에 의해 구출되었을 수도 있습니다.
Many days have passed,
많은 날이 지났고,
but, there is no news of him at all.
하지만 그에 대한 소식은 전혀 없습니다.
He was afraid that bad luck had befallen him.
그는 자신에게 불운이 닥칠까 봐 두려웠습니다.
Maybe Muda Cui has been saved by someone,
어쩌면 Muda Cui가 누군가에 의해 구출되었을 수도 있습니다.
but he needs to recover from his injury
하지만 그는 부상에서 회복해야 해요
and can't come back for a while.
그리고 한동안 돌아오지 못해요 .
That's it, Taozi.
바로 그거야, 타오지.
Don't you calm my heart again.
내 마음을 다시 진정시키지 마십시오.
His body is weak
그 사람 몸이 약해서
and suffered serious injuries.
그리고 심각한 부상을 입었습니다.
In fact, he fell into a rushing river.
사실, 그는 급류하는 강에 빠졌습니다.
Scared...
무서운...
I'm afraid he won't be able to come back again.
그 사람이 다시는 돌아오지 못할까 두렵습니다.
He grew up with me since childhood.
그는 어린 시절부터 나와 함께 자랐습니다 .
In my heart,
내 마음 속에,
he is like
그는 마치
my biological brother
내 생물학적 형제
I didn't think...
나는 생각하지 않았다 ...
Didn't think so
그렇게 생각하지 않았어
he just died.
그는 방금 죽었어.
Enough already.
이미 충분합니다.
I know
알아요
You must be very sad right now.
당신은 지금 매우 슬퍼할 것입니다.
However, you are injured too,
하지만 당신도 부상을 입었고,
you must take medicine
약을 먹어야 해
After you recover,
회복하신 후,
we need to hurry back to Yingzhou to meet the Commander-in-Chief Cui.
우리는 최사령관을 만나기 위해 서둘러 영주로 돌아가야 합니다 .
Evil Li Ni!
그것은 사악하다!
He locked us inside the Taiqing Temple
그는 우리를 태청사 안에 가두었어요
and refuse to let us go.
그리고 우리를 놓아주기를 거부합니다.
He locked us up
그는 우리를 가두었어요
like this prisoner.
이 죄수처럼.
Didn't I say,
내가 말하지 않았나요?
Don't mention him in front of me again?
내 앞에서 그 사람을 다시 언급하지 마세요 ?
Find me some fruit candy.
과일사탕 좀 찾아주세요.
When you come back later,
나중에 다시 오면,
even the medicine has become cold,
약도 차가워졌는데
I can drink quickly.
빨리 마실 수 있어요.
Afraid of no sweets
과자가 없는 것이 두렵다
in this Taiqing Tokong.
이 Taiqing Tokong에서.
I can't go out to buy it.
사러 나갈 수가 없어요 .
What's the word?
무슨 말이에요?
I asked them for me
나는 그들에게 나를 위해 물었다
a little malty
약간 몰티하다
and make maltose for you?
그리고 맥아당을 만들어 줄까?
I'm leaving now.
나는 지금 떠난다.
Why did you pour the medicine?
약은 왜 부었나요?
I am the one who is guilty of causing trouble to the Zhenxi Army.
저는 진시군에 문제를 일으킨 장본인입니다 .
I can die faster if I don't take medicine.
약을 먹지 않으면 더 빨리 죽을 수 있다 .
Isn't this what you want?
이것이 당신이 원하는 것이 아닙니까?
You don't have to save me really.
당신은 정말로 나를 구해줄 필요가 없습니다 .
If Young Master Cui and I die together,
만약 최영선생과 내가 함께 죽는다면,
you can also let go of anger.
분노를 내려놓을 수도 있습니다.
I will definitely save you.
나는 반드시 당신을 구해줄 것입니다.
I don't need you to save me.
당신이 나를 구해줄 필요는 없어요 .
No need on that day,
그날은 필요없어,
no need at this time.
지금은 필요하지 않습니다.
Is the Zhenxi Army extremely furious
Zhenxi 군대는 극도로 분노합니까?
and must kill me and Taozi for revenge?
복수를 위해 나와 Taozi를 죽여야만 합니까 ?
So, you locked me and Taozi up
그래서 넌 나와 Taozi를 가두었지
in this Taiqing Tokong
이 Taiqing Tokong에서
and order your troops to stand guard here?
그리고 당신의 군대에게 이곳을 지키라고 명령하시겠습니까?
Aren't you afraid of your people?
당신은 당신의 사람들을 두려워하지 않습니까?
will rush here to kill us?
우리를 죽이려고 여기로 달려갈까?
Ying,
잉,
I understand that you don't know about the Tong Border thing.
당신이 통 보더(Tong Border)에 대해 모른다는 것을 이해합니다 .
You are arrogant
당신은 거만하다
and used to use overt tactics.
그리고 노골적인 전술을 사용했습니다 .
You will not use this despicable trick.
당신은 이 비열한 속임수를 사용하지 않을 것입니다.
After all, you wouldn't do something that doesn't take care of the whole thing.
결국, 모든 것을 관리하지 않는 일은 하지 않을 것입니다.
Even if it's your fault,
비록 당신의 잘못이라 할지라도,
you will also confess.
너도 고백할 거야.
So, I have slandered you.
그래서 나는 당신을 비방했습니다.
You did not slander me.
당신은 나를 비방하지 않았습니다.
Indeed I am
사실 나는
which causes death
사망을 초래하는 것
your troops
당신의 군대
Just kill me.
그냥 나를 죽여라.
Why are you pious cats to save me?
왜 나를 구하려고 경건한 고양이입니까 ?
Forgive me.
용서 해줘.
I shouldn't mistrust you.
나는 당신을 불신해서는 안됩니다.
However, the incident happened suddenly,
그런데 사건은 갑자기 발생했고,
many Zhenxi Army were killed,
많은 Zhenxi 군대가 사망했습니다.
so i lost my sanity
그래서 난 이성을 잃었어
and misunderstood you.
그리고 당신을 오해했습니다.
Get out. I don't want to see you.
나가세요. 나는 당신을보고 싶지 않습니다.
(Tokong Taiqing)
(도콩타이칭)
Leftenan He,
레프테난 그,
this is indeed a coincidence.
이것은 정말 우연이다.
Originally,
원래,
I'm still nervous
아직도 긴장돼요
for making maltose
맥아당을 만들기 위해
need two days.
이틀이 필요해요.
Didn't think so
그렇게 생각하지 않았어
there is dim sum sent from Luoyang in the kitchen
주방에 낙양에서 보내온 딤섬이 있어요
for Li Ni.
리니를 위해.
I also
나도
take some
조금 가져가
I've felt it,
나는 그것을 느꼈다.
it is not poisonous.
그것은 유독하지 않습니다.
It's quite delicious too.
그것도 꽤 맛있어요.
What happen?
무슨 일이야?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
I have already taken medicine.
나는 이미 약을 먹었습니다.
A rat came in here earlier,
아까 쥐 한 마리가 들어왔어.
I took something for the measles.
홍역 때문에 약을 먹었습니다.
It doesn't touch mice,
쥐에 닿지도 않고,
but things are scattered on the floor.
그런데 물건들이 바닥에 흩어져 있어요.
Look,
바라보다,
ketua panglima Tentera Zhenxi itu
케투아 판글리마 텐테라 젠시 이투
disguised as
로 위장한
rats too.
쥐도.
Rats bring fruit sweets here
쥐들이 과일 과자를 여기로 가져옵니다
and hurt Lieutenant He's heart.
그리고 중위의 마음에 상처를 입혔습니다.
My medicine is useless.
내 약은 쓸모가 없습니다.
Enough already,
이미 충분히,
I'm going to boil the medicine for you again.
내가 다시 약을 끓여줄게요.
Did you go to Taiqing Temple again?
또 태청사에 가셨나요?
Any news from Yingzhou?
잉저우에서 소식은 없나요?
Cui Yi is indeed cunning.
Cui Yi는 참으로 교활합니다.
Half of Sun Jing's army
손징군 절반
He has been deleted.
그는 삭제되었습니다.
The other half was hunted by Cui Yi,
나머지 절반은 최이(Cui Yi)에게 사냥당했고,
fought while retreating, almost reached Fuzhou.
후퇴하면서 싸워 거의 복주에 이르렀다.
What did Cui Yi say?
최이가 뭐라고 말했어요?
He quickly agreed to our terms.
그는 우리의 조건에 빠르게 동의했습니다.
However, this cunning one
그런데 이 교활한 놈이
want us to capture Cui Li alive.
우리가 Cui Li를 생포하도록 해주세요.
It feels like he wants to
그 사람이 그러고 싶은 것 같아
revenge for his son.
아들에 대한 복수.
My eldest sister can't
큰언니는 못해요
bear heavy responsibility.
무거운 책임을 집니다.
Cui Li hid where he was.
Cui Li는 그가 있던 곳에 숨었습니다.
If nothing happens, then Cui Li is safe.
아무 일도 일어나지 않으면 Cui Li는 안전합니다.
However, if anything happens,
그러나 만일 무슨 일이 생기면,
he will definitely hand over Cui Li.
그는 확실히 Cui Li를 넘겨줄 것입니다.
Of.
의.
Shiqi,
시치,
several people in Tokong Taiqing
토콩 타이칭의 여러 사람들
not colluding with Cui Lin,
추이린과 공모하지 않고
even those people who
심지어 그 사람들도
Cui Yi wants to protect.
최이는 보호하고 싶어한다.
I will
그럴게요
explain to others.
다른 사람들에게 설명하십시오.
Also,
또한,
Cui Yi has agreed to
Cui Yi가 동의했습니다.
strike with us,
우리와 함께 파업하고,
can we take revenge for those who died.
죽은 이들에게 복수할 수 있을까요 ?
However,
하지만,
well you don't always go to Taiqing Temple anymore.
글쎄, 당신은 더 이상 태청사에 항상 가지 않습니다 .
Leftenan He
레프테난 그
the Cui Family Army people,
Cui 가족 군대 사람들,
you are the commander in chief of the Zhenxi Army.
당신은 Zhenxi 군대의 총사령관입니다.
Not good
안좋다
you hang out closely.
당신은 밀접하게 어울리고 있습니다.
I told you once
내가 한 번 말했잖아
which I feel guilty about him.
나는 그에 대해 죄책감을 느낍니다.
However, you have to remember,
그러나 기억해야 할 것은,
The emperor has ascended the throne now.
이제 황제가 왕위에 올랐습니다.
You are his son,
당신은 그의 아들이고,
ketua panglima Tentera Zhenxi.
케투아 판글리마 텐테라 젠시(Ketua panglima).
It's impossible for you to marry a woman from the Cui Family Army.
최씨군 여자와 결혼하는 것은 불가능하다 .
Even if you take her as your wife, you can't.
그 사람을 아내로 삼아도 그렇게 할 수 없습니다.
Since you know that,
당신도 그걸 알기 때문에,
why not end your relationship earlier?
관계를 더 일찍 끝내는 게 어때요 ?
Shiqi,
시치,
you are very clear that
당신은 아주 분명해요
your mate
네 짝
will be blessed by his majesty.
그의 위엄으로 축복을 받을 것이다.
Selected girl
선택된 소녀
definitely a girl from a famous family in the capital.
확실히 수도의 유명한 가문 출신의 소녀였습니다.
Even if you make a request with him,
그 사람에게 부탁을 해도
he will also find you
그 사람도 당신을 찾을 거예요
someone worthy of being a mistress.
여주인이 될 자격이 있는 사람.
Shiqi,
시치,
you can't possibly marry him.
당신은 그 사람과 결혼할 수 없어요.
It is early that we discuss this now.
지금 이 문제를 논의하기에는 이르다 .
♪If you've forgotten the twinkling light♪
♪반짝이는 빛을 잊으셨다면♪
♪Tunggu kenangan♪
♪퉁구 케난간♪
♪Shattered and sunk♪
♪부서져 가라앉았어♪
♪The spots that remain on your heart♪
♪당신의 마음속에 남아있는 얼룩들 ♪
♪Penarikan itu♪
♪페나리칸 이투♪
♪It's my objection♪
♪이의가 있어요♪
♪If longing is never left behind♪
♪그리움이 결코 버리지 않는다면♪
♪Longing to go back to the earliest times♪
♪ 가장 옛날로 돌아가고 싶은 그리움 ♪
♪The warmth that fate once had♪
♪운명이 가졌던 따뜻함 ♪
♪I want to keep it for you♪
♪당신을 위해 간직하고 싶어요♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪사랑이 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪We once promised♪
♪한번 약속했었지♪
♪Even though love hurts me♪
♪사랑이 나를 아프게 해도♪
♪I must live for you too♪
♪나도 당신을 위해 살아야 해요♪
♪Following faces in memories♪
♪추억 속 얼굴을 따라가다♪
♪Waiting is my obsession♪
♪기다리는 것이 나의 집착♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪사랑이 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪A promise kept for you♪
♪당신을 위한 약속♪
♪Terbalikkan karma♪
♪테르발리칸 카르마♪
♪Loving for you without regret♪
♪후회없이 사랑합니다♪
♪I'm willing to leave it for you♪
♪당신에게 맡기고 싶습니다♪
♪I'm always waiting for you to answer me♪
♪항상 답변을 기다리고 있어요 ♪
♪If love still remembers♪
♪사랑이 아직도 기억한다면♪
♪A promise kept for you♪
♪당신을 위한 약속♪
♪Terbalikkan karma♪
♪테르발리칸 카르마♪
♪Loving for you without regret♪
♪후회없이 사랑합니다♪
♪I'm willing to leave it for you♪
♪당신에게 맡기고 싶습니다♪
♪I'm always waiting for you to answer me♪
♪항상 답변을 기다리고 있어요 ♪